<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sharven Prasad Dhanasekar</title><link>https://sharvenp.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sharven Prasad Dhanasekar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sharvenp.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>md.it</title><link>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/md.it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/md.it/</guid><description>During my co-op internship as a Web Developer at Environment and Climate Change Canada, I found myself writing a lot of markdown for discussions, design documents, and bug reports. HackMD.io is my always first choice for writing markdown documents, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted a desktop/offline version of HackMD&amp;hellip; so I decided to make one 😉
I saw this as an excellent opportunity to learn ElectronJS, which is a framework for creating cross-platform desktop applications using a web development framework of your choice.</description></item><item><title>UofTalk</title><link>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/uoftalk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/uoftalk/</guid><description>As part of my software engineering course, I worked in a team of 7 people to build an app from scratch.
We decided to make a social networking platform where users can match with other users that share similar preferences in music, video games, movies, and humour.
We implemented various features where users can create profiles, chat with other users, form groups, and many more. We also added Spotify API integration where users OAuth into their Spotify accounts and display their top 5 most listened artists on their profile.</description></item><item><title>Sentimuse</title><link>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/sentimuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/sentimuse/</guid><description>Developed an AI model as part of an independent research course that understands the positive/negative sentiment in a given piece of text and generates music that fits the sentiment!
The AI uses a Sentiment Analysis model to first understand the sentiment of the text and then based on the sentiment, it picks a pre-trained music generation model to generate music specific to that sentiment.
The Sentiment Analysis model consists of a bi-directional GRU Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) that creates an embedding of the given text and then passes this embedding into a fully-connected Neural Net that classifies the sentiment.</description></item><item><title>Self-Steering Car</title><link>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/self-steering-car/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sharvenp.github.io/projects/self-steering-car/</guid><description>Developed an AI agent that learned how to steer a car along a randomly generated race track using Reinforcement Learning.
Reinforcement Learning is the process of training an agent to complete a task purely by supplying it rewards/punishment. If the agent does something that is desired, it receives a positive reward, and alternatively, if it does something that isn&amp;rsquo;t desired, it receives a negative reward.
This may sound familiar, and that&amp;rsquo;s because this is exactly how animals and humans learn!</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://sharvenp.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sharvenp.github.io/about/</guid><description>Currently a 4th year Computer Science student at the University of Toronto.
Passionate about developing apps and tinkering with new technologies (Hugo just came out, so I decided to create this website using it 😊).
Head over to the projects page to see some of my notable side projects!</description></item></channel></rss>